Women's movement collection (Anne Roberts collector)
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Women's movement collection (Anne Roberts collector)
1969 - 1975
F-166
Q105635657
13 cm of textual records 13 newspapers
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
TERMS OF USE AND REPRODUCTION Copyright subsists in all or some of the records and the donor, Anne Roberts, has retained copyright ownership. Generally, the donor only owns copyright to the works s/he authored and not necessarily to all the records that comprise this fonds or collection. The Archives can make a single copy only for private study, research, or other fair dealing use by a patron. The donor has granted the Archives permission to release her contact information to those researchers wishing to ask permission to copy and use the copyright protected materials for a different purpose. Speak with the Reference Archivist for details.
Roberts, Anne
Anne Roberts became a member of the Vancouver Women's Caucus in 1969. She worked on The Pedestal, a feminist newspaper published by the Women's Caucus, and participated in the working women's group. Roberts played a key role in organizing the Indo-Chinese Women's Conference, held in Vancouver in 1971. The conference brought together Canadian, American, and Indo-Chinese women to protest the Vietnamese War. Roberts was interviewed by Frances Wasserlein for her 1990 master's thesis, "An Arrow Aimed at the Heart" The Vancouver Women's Caucus and the Abortion Campaign 1969-1971. The transcript of that interview is contained in the Frances Wasserlein fonds, F-162.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the collection is based on its contents and the name of the collector.
Fonds consists of material acquired by Anne Roberts as a member of Vancouver Women's Caucus. Includes minutes, correspondence, flyers, pamphlets, reprints, news clippings, briefs, position papers, copies of The Pedestal, and other documents.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Roberts, Anne; Vancouver Women's Caucus; Women
Anne Roberts gave the material to Frances Wasserlein for use in her thesis and for subsequent donation to the Archives. Roberts formally donated the material in 2002.
All accessions have been processed as of March 2006. No further accruals are expected.
Also see the inventories for the Frances Wasserlein fonds, F-162; Andrea Lebowitz's women's movement collection, F-164; and Candace Parker's women's movement collection, F-165.
The files are open with no restrictions.
A file list is available for the textual records and an item list is available for the periodicals.
A short biographical account of Anne Roberts from Frances Wasserlein's thesis is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
- Abortion, 1971 - 1975; F-166-0-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
  published
  Textual records
  Open
- Articles by Anne Roberts, 1970; F-166-0-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Indo-Chinese Women's Conference 1/3, 1970 - 1971; F-166-0-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Indo-Chinese Women's Conference 2/3, 1970 - 1971; F-166-0-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Indo-Chinese Women's Conference 3/3, 1970 - 1971; F-166-0-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Vancouver Women's Caucus, 1969 - 1971; F-166-0-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Women's Liberation - other cities, 1969; F-166-0-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Working Women, 1969 - 1972; F-166-0-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 166-1)
- Georgia Straight, 1970; F-166-0-0-0-9 (Newspaper box 166-2)
  - Georgia Straight, vol. 4, no. 103, April 1970; F-166-0-0-0-9-1 (Newspaper box 166-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item1.
- The Pedestal, 1969 - 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10 (Newspaper box 166-3)
  - The Pedestal, vol. 1 no. 2, 1969; F-166-0-0-0-10-1 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item2.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 1 no. 2, 1969; F-166-0-0-0-10-2 (Newspaper box 166-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item3.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 1, February 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-3 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item4.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 2, March 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-4 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item5.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 3, April 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-5 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item6.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 4, May 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-6 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item7.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 5, June 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-7 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item8.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 6, July 1970 - August 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-8 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item9.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 7, September 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-9 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item10.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 9, November 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-10 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item11.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 9, November 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-11 (Newspaper box 166-4)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item12.
  - The Pedestal, vol. 2 no. 10, December 1970; F-166-0-0-0-10-12 (Newspaper box 166-3)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-166-item13.